limaohio.com 2017-12-02

# Privacy | Civitas Media - civitasmedia.com

**CIVITAS MEDIA, LLC**

**PRIVACY POLICY**

**Last Updated: 03/15/2016**

_**Privacy Policy Overview**_

Civitas Media, LLC (“Civitas,” “us,” or “we”) knows that you care how information about you is used and shared and respects the privacy of the visitors to the [www.www.civitasmedia.com](http://www.www.civitasmedia.com/) website (this “Site”). We have created this Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) to demonstrate our commitment to privacy and security and supplement our [Terms of Service](http://www.www.civitasmedia.com/terms) (“Terms of Service”) for the Site. This Privacy Policy is an agreement between Civitas and you, as the user of this Site (“you”). It explains what information of yours will be collected by us when you use this Site, how the information will be used, how you can control the collection, how we may change this Privacy Policy, and the steps we take to ensure that your personal information is protected. We request that you read this Privacy Policy carefully.

In this Privacy Policy, “personal information” means any information by which you can be identified or contacted, including but not limited to, your name (first and last), mailing address, email address, telephone number, billing information, etc.

All activities which you engage in on this Site are voluntary. You are not required to provide any personal information to us unless you choose to access features or services on the Site which require the information. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Service posted on this Site, then you should immediately exit this Site and discontinue using the Site. By your use of this Site, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy as well as to our Terms of Service. The Terms of Service of this Site are expressly incorporated herein by reference and made a part of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through this Site and does not apply to any information we may collect from you at any place other than this Site.

_**Information We Collect**_

**User-Provided Information** **:** In order to access certain interactive features of our website we may collect personal information, such as your name, email address, street address, age and gender identification or photographs, when, for example, you register for or subscribe to certain forums, products or services or [contact customer service](mailto:CIVHR@www.www.civitasmedia.com).

**Cookies Information:** When you visit the Site, we may send one or more cookies – a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Site. A cookie does not collect personal information about you. We use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Site or services may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

**Log File Information:** Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. When you register with or view our Site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses or other device identifiers, browser information, Internet Service Provider (“ISP”), operating system, location, date/time stamp, clickstream data, referring/exit pages and URLs, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

_**How We Use Your Information**_

Certain features of our Site require that you provide personal information in order to access circulation tools, e-mail blasts, e-ditions, and provide user comments. Therefore, we may use personal information to provide you access to such content or features. For example, if you choose to post a comment on the Site, subscribe to an e-mail blast, or register for a contest, we may use your personal information to create a user profile. These are just a few examples and do not represent all of the ways in which Civitas may use your personal information. 

Any personal information or content you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Site (for instance, any user content you post) becomes available to the public via the Site and our business partners. User content includes, but is not limited to, reviews, testimonials, comments, photos, videos, biographical information, blog posts, social media posts, etc. If you remove user content, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored your user content.

By providing Civitas your email address, you consent to our using the email address provided to send you Site and service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. We may also use your email address to send you other messages including, but not limited to account status, legal updates, changes to features of the Site or services, special offers or promotions, or other account information. 

_**Third-Party Disclosure & Analytics**_

Civitas utilizes certain third-parties for purposes of data collection, and these third parties may have access to user information provided to Civitas. By continuing to utilize interactive services on our Site you consent to your information possibly becoming available to such third parties. These third parties may include [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) and [Quantcast](https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/), which may provide incidental information to social media cites, such as but not limited to [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en), [Google+](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). 

Civitas may use certain information about you and/or your user content without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as analyzing how the Site is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing advertisements and promotions. 

Civitas reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor the user content you post on the Site. Civitas has the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason including, without limitation, if in its sole opinion, such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or our Terms of Service, or to protect or defend Civitas’s rights or property or those of any third party. Civitas also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.

We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our Site and services; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and traffic; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems reported by our users or engineers that are associated with the IP addresses controlled by a specific web company or ISP; and (f) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in.

_**How We Share Your Information**_

**Personally Identifiable Information:** Civitas will not rent or sell your personal information to others. We disclose potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to those of our employees, contractors (including website operators), affiliated organizations, service providers and other third parties that provide support services to us or help us market our products and services, administer our programs and operations, fulfill your requests, administer surveys, or process any other information on our behalf to provide services available at our Site.

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, Civitas will not disclose personal information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law, comply with legal process served on us or our affiliates, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities; (b) to enforce our Terms of Service, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, or to protect the security or integrity of our Site; and (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Civitas, our users or others.

We fully cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our Site or services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful, as determined in our sole discretion. Release of your personal information for security purposes, as described in this Privacy Policy to any person or entity under any circumstances shall be based on a determination made solely by us, exercising our own discretion, permission for which is expressly granted by you to us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain services.

_**How We Protect Your Information**_

Civitas utilizes commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards in line with industry standards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Civitas or the Site and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, Civitas makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. While we strive to protect your personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online.

_**User Choices About Your Information**_

When using our Site you have the choice to update certain aspects of your personal information that you provide. For example, you may be able to update personal information such as your e-mail address when you post comments to our Site. However, if you have posted or submitted a news story to our Site under a former e-mail address prior to any updates, the previous e-mail address may remain.

**Do Not Track Disclosure:** Some browsers or other tools include “Do Not Track” (DNT) features which, when turned on, send a signal to websites you visit indicating that you do not wish to be tracked across websites over time. The Worldwide Web Consortium (W3C) has been working with industry groups and regulators to develop a DNT browser technology standard to provide a common understanding as to how to interpret the DNT signals, but to date no standard has been adopted. Since there is no standard at this time, Civitas does not currently respond to DNT signals. Civitas will follow the progress of the W3C in developing the standard.

_**Children’s Privacy (COPPA)**_

Civitas does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 should provide any personal information to or on this Site. In the event we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information promptly. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please [contact us](http://www.www.civitasmedia.com/contact). We encourage parents and guardians of children under 18 to regularly check and monitor their children’s use of email and other activities online.

_**Links to Other Websites**_

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site or the information or content contained therein. Civitas may provide links to other websites to you solely as a convenience, and the inclusion of linked sites does not imply endorsement by Civitas of any of the linked sites. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Site to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our Site, is subject to that website’s own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding. We do not ensure the security of your personal information if you visit websites not belonging to Civitas.

_**California Online Privacy Protection Act of 2003 (CalOPPA)**_

The California Online Privacy Protection Act, or CalOPPA, is the first state law in the United States to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. 

See more at [https://oag.ca.gov/privacy/privacy-laws](https://oag.ca.gov/privacy/privacy-laws)

In accordance with CalOPPA, we agree to the following:

You can visit our Site anonymously, though this may limit the content you may see. We will provide a link to this Privacy Policy at all times on the first significant page upon entering our Site. This link will appear in a prominent location and include the word “Privacy” so that it may be easily found.

_**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**_

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes, modifications, additions, or deletions to this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately on their posting to this Site. Your continued use of the Site after we post any such modifications will constitute your acknowledgment of the modified policy and your agreement to abide and be bound by the modified policy. We will revise the “Last Updated” date found at the beginning of this Privacy Policy when it is updated.

_**Contact Us**_

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, your dealings with this Site, or wish to update us with your preferences, you may contact us via the [Contacting Us link](http://www.www.civitasmedia.com/contact) or by phone by calling (704) 897-6020.  You may also write to us at:

Civitas Media, LLC

130 Harbour Place Drive Suite 300

Davidson, NC 28036

We ask that you not disclose any sensitive personal information (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, criminal background or trade union membership) when contacting us.
